# **KEVIN McGUIRE**

https://kpmcguire.github.io # kpmcguire@gmail.com # Ithaca, NY # 773-600-1965

A well-rounded Web Developer with extensive experience on the front end of the stack, including Design, UX, and Web Accessibility, adept at learning new technologies and crafting sites with a delightful user experience.

## Work Experience

## Web Designer

Cornell University – Ithaca, NY March 2017 to March 2019

- \*\* Worked with a team to develop procedures for successfully remediating old websites and creating new websites with accessibility from the start
- \*\* Provided detailed estimates to keep projects on budget, and communicated to project managers when work was running behind
- \* Designed and developed websites from the beginning stages through launch
- # Successfully trained end users on how to maintain their own websites

## Lead User Interface Developer

GiveGab, Inc. – Ithaca, NY January 2014 to March 2017

- ★ Consistently worked to improve the UX of the product
- ★ Lead an initiative to implement accessibility features
- ★ Trained coworkers on how to UI components
- ₩ Worked on a team to implement a site-wide responsive redesign

# Front-End Developer

Punchkick Interactive – Chicago, IL February 2010 to December 2010

- ₩ Wrote HTML/CSS for mobile websites
- \* Performed extensive testing on a wide variety of mobile devices
- ₩ HTML email implementation & testing

#### Web Production Designer

Mauge, Inc – Chicago, IL October 2005 to August 2008

- ₩ Wrote HTML/CSS for websites

- ₩ HTML email implementation & testing

#### Education

#### Bachelor of Arts

Central Michigan University Graphic Design/Philosophy

#### **Skills**

Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign, Semantic HTML, CSS/SCSS, Ruby on Rails, jQuery, Vue.js, Backbone, Gulp, Git